<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The messenger of an universal peace: or a third message to the Philadelphian Society. By J. Lead</title>
            <author>Lead, Jane, 1623-1704.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 78KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 51 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A88857</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99896429</idno>
  <idno type="VID">154250</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240943089</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing L788</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R230692</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99896429</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99896429e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A88857)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 154250)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2407:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The messenger of an universal peace: or a third message to the Philadelphian Society. By J. Lead</title>
                  <author>Lead, Jane, 1623-1704.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[24], 72 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for the booksellers of London and Westminster,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1698.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Wing reports title as "A messenger of an universal peace."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="corporate_name">Philadelphian Society (London, England) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Protestant churches --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-10 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="book_plate">
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:1"/>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>two classical figures (Athena and possibly Apollo) contemplating a small nude statue</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>O Libri, soli liberales et liberi, commodissimi magistri, qui omni petenti tribuitis, qui omnes manumittitis vobis sedulo servientes, Vos. Arca Noe!</p>
            <p>Vos vera Scala Iacob!</p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:2"/>
            <p>THE MESSENGER OF An Universal Peace: OR A Third Message TO THE <hi>Philadelphian Society.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>By <hi>J. LEAD.</hi>
            </p>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>John xiv. 27.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>My PEACE I give unto You.</p>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for the Booksellers of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Westminster,</hi> 1698.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:3"/>
            <head>An Admonition TO THE READER.</head>
            <p>THe <hi>Wisdom</hi> of God and his good Providence have been working most deeply &amp; admirably in all the Ages of the World to this present time for the Restitution of Man and his lapsed Creation: to bring forth in the latter days thereof the compleat and perfect Redemption from the Curse of Sin, and that Thraldom and Vanity, the effect thereof, to which the Creature has been thus long subject; the whole Creation groaning and travailing in pain till Now: yet in good hope of being one day deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered
<pb facs="tcp:154250:4"/> from the Bondage of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruption into the Glorious <hi>Liberty</hi> of the Sons of God; and waiting in Patience for the Manifestation of them. These secret <hi>Springs</hi> and Workings have been little ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>served indeed by the Eye of the World: but as they draw near to the accomplishment and product of their great <hi>End;</hi> as they come nearer to their <hi>Centre,</hi> those Wheels of Providence and the Divine Wis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom move more strongly and vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gorously, and also more discernibly to the Children and Sons of Wis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom; for the bringing forth the <hi>Finishing</hi> Wonders, and the Last Glorious Scenes and Manifestation of the great Redemption obtained and wrought out for us by our Lord <hi>Jesus:</hi> which is yet but little un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derstood or comprehended of what vast Extent and force it is. All that is expected by the Generality of
<pb facs="tcp:154250:4"/> Christians, is to be preserved and assisted by the Grace of God in this miserable Life, so as to gain the upper hand of our Sins and Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruptions; to maintain a continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed War against them, and be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways getting ground; and at last to lay down our sinful Heads in the Dust, transferring all our <hi>Glorious</hi> Expectations to another World: but little dreaming that the great Conquerour of Death and Hell, and Treader upon the Serpent and all the Powers and Principalities of the dark World would make an open shew of it even in This. That he will not be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent to suffer them always to Reign even in this lower World, but by degrees, and in his own determi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate time, chase them out, and bind them up, and triumph over them in the sight of all men: af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter that the time allotted to the
<pb facs="tcp:154250:5"/>
               <hi>Beast,</hi> the <hi>Dragon</hi> and <hi>Antichrist</hi> shall be fulfilled. That the mighty Power and Vertue of his All-suf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient Sacrifice and Death shall at last totally expel the Venom, and pluck up the very <hi>Root</hi> of Sin out of his Members; after that all the Mystical Seals of the Book of the Lamb shall be opened; and the Wisdom and Love of God shall be poured forth as a <hi>Deluge</hi> upon the Earth; and the <hi>Holy Spirit</hi> so long banisht from the Christian World (the greatest Sign and Instance of its woful Apostacy) shall again Return as at first, in a New and Second <hi>Pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tecost;</hi> and go on and encrease for the full completion of the Prophe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies relating to the Glorious and <hi>Triumphant</hi> State of the Church here on Earth. That hereby he shall empower and inable many of his Servants as the younger Sons
<pb facs="tcp:154250:5"/> of the <hi>Resurrection</hi> to follow Him their Head; and as the Great <hi>Enoch</hi> and <hi>Elijah</hi> had done be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, to shew the World the Possi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility thereof; to break through the bounds of this Mortal Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciple, and with Him triumph over Mortality and Death, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turning it that Sarcasm of the Apostle in its full extent, O Death where is thy Sting? O Grave where is thy Victory? These are they who shall stand as <hi>Saviours</hi> upon Mount <hi>Sion,</hi> as the Prophet <hi>Obadiah</hi> has foreseen and fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>told us, <hi>Vers. 21.</hi> They shall stand as <hi>Saviours,</hi> subordinate to their Mighty One; being thus Saved, and hitherto Redeem'd by Him; and from him receiving Power, and becoming highly Instrumen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal to help others to break through and follow them. O thrice Bles<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed
<pb facs="tcp:154250:6"/> and Happy are they that are Partakers of this <hi>First Resur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection!</hi> that shall be so near, and Intimately united with Christ, so filled with him, and so made One with him, as to co-operate under Him, (more truly himself working in them,) for the Resto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration of their Brethren. To whom having given Himself, he will deny Nothing; but will in a Wonderful and Mysterious man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>r Write his own <hi>Name</hi> upon them, and make them Partakers even of his own Glory, according to his gracious Condescension and Intent, to all his true Members at their full Perfection and Consum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation, declared and offered to his Father in his Prayer before his Suffering, <hi>John 17.21.</hi> &amp;c. <hi>That they all may be One, as thou Father art in me, and I in Thee, that they also may be One
<pb facs="tcp:154250:6"/> in Us; that the World may be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that thou hast sent me. And the Glory which thou gavest me I have given them; that they may be One even as We are One. I in them and Thou in me, that they may be made Perfect in One, and that the World may know that Thou hast sent me, and hast Loved them as thou hast Lo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved me.</hi> This Prayer of our Lord was First for his immediate Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciples, and secondly for all his Members: accordingly His Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciples were after his Ascension taken into such a Degree of this Ʋnion, and had the <hi>Name</hi> and <hi>Power</hi> of God so Engraven upon them; as to act all Wonders in the Power of <hi>Omnipotency</hi> in the Holy Spirit. Whereby the World might know that <hi>Jesus</hi> whom they preached was sent of God. So likewise at this day upon the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn
<pb facs="tcp:154250:7"/> of the <hi>Triumphant</hi> King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of Christ will this be done in a far greater measure in the Calling, Sealing and Impowering a New <hi>Disciplehood</hi> that shall bear up unitedly the <hi>Banner</hi> of Love with the Inscription of the <hi>Royal</hi> Name: Even the Great Ensign the <hi>Standard</hi> of God, which they shall bear in the sight of all Nations, in such Majesty, Might and Glory, and accompa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nied with such Renewed Powers and Amazing Wonders of the <hi>Holy Ghost,</hi> with such Invince<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able force and Prevalence of Truth in the <hi>Demonstration</hi> of the <hi>Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit,</hi> and in the sweet and meek Light of the Divine <hi>Wisdom,</hi> breaking forth in its Lustre and Beauty, and piercing into all the Secrets and Mysteries both of <hi>Temporary</hi> and <hi>Eternal</hi> Nature <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> shall effectually convince the
<pb facs="tcp:154250:7"/> World not only of the Truth, but of the vast and <hi>boundless</hi> Efficacy of the Redemption wrought out by the true Son of God and Man, the Lord Jesus. So that his Gospel shall now be not only Publish'd, but received and submitted to by <hi>all</hi> Nations, Tongues and Languages: so as that at the Name of <hi>Jesus</hi> every Knee shall bow; the <hi>Heathen</hi> being now actually given Him by God for an Inheritance, and the uttermost Parts of the Earth for a Possession; confessing Him to be Christ; and <hi>Lord;</hi> and <hi>God,</hi> Blessed for ever.</p>
            <p>For this the <hi>Trumpets</hi> are gone forth, and are going forth, and will continue to do so, waxing louder and louder; for the Rou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing and Awakening the Sleepy World; and especially the Luke<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warm, degenerate, and <hi>Formal</hi> Christendom: that a Refreshment
<pb facs="tcp:154250:8"/> and Revival may be of the almost expiring Life of <hi>Jesus</hi> in it; and principally of the more <hi>Inward</hi> and <hi>Spiritual</hi> Rest thereof, which is be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num'd and frozen Part even to Death in the Hearts of its Professors. The <hi>Holy Spirit</hi> of God is now <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turning</hi> and has sent forth his <hi>Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses,</hi> though at first as <hi>Infants,</hi> stammering forth in Weakness the first and lower degrees of its Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifestation, and Approach, Thro' whom it now Calls: and it will not give over calling and crying, till it shall make those that have any sence of Good, and of the Love of God even asham'd of their coldness and backwardness to meet it; and till it have excited in 'em; and melted 'em into a holy Regret and Grief for the unkind and rough treatment; with which at first many of the Servants of God, through Prejudice and Zeal
<pb facs="tcp:154250:8"/> for pre-conceived and establish'd Opinions, will receive it. It will proceed in all the mildness, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bearance, gentleness, kindness, and condescension of Love, as the true Spirit of <hi>Jesus;</hi> returning good for evil, love for hatred, ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligation for despite. Even till by forbearing and suffering at the Hands of its Opposers, yet still loving, doing good, and still meek<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly pressing them notwithstanding to yield themselves to the Will of God, at last the Heart of Flint may dissolve, and the rough <hi>Esau</hi> be brought to weep upon the Neck of <hi>Jacob</hi> and <hi>Joseph</hi> be acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledg'd and own'd by his cruel Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren. For this is the wonderful Day of the Manifestation of <hi>Love;</hi> it is the Ministration of the <hi>Love</hi> of <hi>God:</hi> wherein its mighty power and prevalency above the Wrath and Justice shall be displaid; in
<pb facs="tcp:154250:9"/> the more effectual Conversion and subduing the Hearts of Men; and tha Triumphs of Mercy against Judgment in behalf of all, even the <hi>greatest Sinners</hi> that will sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit themselves, and make use of the vast Advantages and Tenders that will be made them. Yet even Love tho' in its Day of Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cession unto Victory it Predomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate and go foremost, yet <hi>Justice</hi> and <hi>Judgment</hi> must attend and follow it: for here the <hi>Jealousie</hi> of <hi>God</hi> is most concern'd to resent and avenge the Contempt and Injury of the Obstinate and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bellious to his greatest Love and Goodness. He will now Offer his Spirit Freely to all, even in an ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>traordinary manner, without Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stinction of Sex, Age, or Person, even upon the Hand-maids and Servants; yea, out of the Mouths of Babes and Sucklings shall his
<pb facs="tcp:154250:9"/> Praise he sounded forth. Every degree of Injury against the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Ghost, the <hi>Dove</hi> of <hi>God,</hi> or Spirit of <hi>Love</hi> has a peculiar Evil in it: because this is the greatest offer of God, and consequently the obstinate rejecting it, after its full Evidence shall be given, most dangerous and fatal. But Love always preceding, and doing all that is possible beforehand, will abundantly clear the Floor, taking to its self all the good Grain, all that either were good, or could possibly be made so; at least at that Time and Offer. And so Love according to its own Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, will proceed bearing and overlooking the evil: tho' after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward upon the Approach of At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tendant Justice, it must pass the Fire, and suffer loss, according to its degree of malignity; and this
<pb facs="tcp:154250:10"/> whether in single Persons or Ʋni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Bodies.</p>
            <p>But here is the difference be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the former and this <hi>Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stration</hi> of the <hi>Spirit:</hi> that then it descended at Once upon the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles in full maturity, strength and power; but being since lost in the Church through the Apostacy, and decay of pure and Primitive Christianity; it is to be Revived again in the Church after ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther manner, in the new chosen <hi>Disciplehood:</hi> who shall be ena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled to Recover it again by an orderly Process backwards by the way in which it declined; and through the Ordinary Assistance of it, rise by the degrees of true Regeneration to the Extraordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, so that the <hi>Holy Ghost</hi> shall be form'd in 'em; not as a <hi>transient</hi> Gust, but as a <hi>Birth</hi> of Power sixt and Innate in them; daily ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing
<pb facs="tcp:154250:10"/> and growing in 'em to a more full and perfect Stature; and mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiplying it self in them and others in all its various Gifts and Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>difestations, with many unheard of and surprizing Wonders.</p>
            <p>Now blessed be God our Father, and the Lord Christ our Redeemer, who has given his Church at this day to see and experience the Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginnings of these things: and to feel the Holy Powers of his Spirit returning again, and in some de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grees of its Extraordinary Opera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion exerting it self in a few select Members. Who notwithstanding all the opposition and contempt of others, have born their Testimony, and cannot but still bear it. Some Accounts hereof have been published to the World: and there is yet much more behind to be decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, as it shall be able to receive it, and as God shall open its way.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:11"/>
            <p>He has done done much already by the Hand of this Eminent Instrument, the Author of this and the Foregoing <hi>Messages,</hi> and other sublime and Spirit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ual Treatises: and in this has sent forth a Gracious inviting Call, and earnest Excitement to all the Churches, both of this Nation, and others, to Return from whence they have fallen; even to the Spirit and truth of his Worship, and from the <hi>Form</hi> of Christian Piety to the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward <hi>Life</hi> and <hi>Power</hi> thereof: setting forth his Gracious intention, and his great Love, and the future greater Mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>festation of it in the Now opening Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stration of <hi>Love;</hi> that they may pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pare themselues to meet their Lord and be fill'd with the Bl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ssings of it: laying aside their Heats and Divisions which pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed only from a furious Zeal, and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinate concern for the Outward Shell and Husk of Religion, and freely Ʋni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting and Embracing each other in the unity of Peace and Charity which is the true <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Character and State.</p>
            <p>And for this Moderation and temper of the divided Brethren, particularly of this Nation, towards each other, a pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culiar
<pb facs="tcp:154250:11"/> Argument may be drawn from the Manner of Gods address and call to 'em in this Message. Where tho' the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided Parties themselves (at least too many among them) will scarce afford each other a part of their Charity, or allow them to be Churches of God; but brand each other Mutually with the odi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Names of <hi>Hereticks, Schismaticks Enthusiasts;</hi> or meer <hi>Formalities, Anti-Christian</hi> and <hi>Idolatrous:</hi> we find God here Graciously overlooking the faults and flaws of their particular Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dations and Constitution, and tho' he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minds 'em all of their Insufficiency and declension from the Spirit of Religion yet owns them all freely as his Church and People. Giving herein a Pattern of the divine Goodness and Condescension to all; that whom he disdains not to Embrace in the Arms of his Love, we should not any way exclude from our Charity and Christian Affection.</p>
            <p>The Repeated Calls of God at this time are loud and earnest: the Cause to be engaged in Noble and Glorious. Yet with its Proportionable Hazards and Difficulties. The <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Crown
<pb facs="tcp:154250:12"/> most weighty, and worthy of the highest Adventures and Atchievements in the Hero's of Divine Faith and Love; and for further Encouragement to all, the first Difficulties are past and conquer'd; the Gulph is broke through; the <hi>Phila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delphian</hi> Door is already opened, and a Passage made for Participation of the Powers of the World to come. The Young and Infant Dove Now flutters her Wing, sweetly inviting as yet in a soft still Voice and breath of Love: as it were calling for Assistance, to the help of the Lord against the Mighty: Now is it that the Spirit and the Bride say Come; and those that hear it Repeat that Call, and say Come. And whosoever will may come, and drink of this New Spring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Fountain; of the Waters of Life freely: O who will lend their Hand; who will break through the Clouds and Mist, and pay their first Homage and early Attendance; to meet and bring Her in, to partake of her first Smiles and Favours; her first and Tenderest Love? Who is Emulous through a holy Zeal and Ambition to be nearest the Heart, and lie in the Bosom of Divine
<pb facs="tcp:154250:12"/> Love? To such as shall reach this happy Station, the highest Honours in the <hi>Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>umphant</hi> Kingdom do of Right belong; even the Supreme and Royal <hi>Unction,</hi> both to the <hi>Sacerdotal, Prophetical,</hi> and <hi>Kingly</hi> Dignity. 'Tis not to be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected that the Holy Spirit now Return<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing again to the Church, after the break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing open the <hi>Seals,</hi> and the time of <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tichrist</hi> expiring, should be tied up to, or take up any of the many Forms of Man's Invention; being now to open, though by degrees, a new and more per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect Dispensation. Here then will be the great Difficulty. Every Party be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing deeply Prejudiced for their own Esta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blishment, will thereby be too apt, as the <hi>Jews</hi> did at our Saviour's first Coming; to set up their own Law as if it were per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect, and needed no further Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pletion, against the Spirit of God coming to fulfil it. And many being well set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tled and provided for in their present State, will have a shrewd Temptation from thence to endeavour the Continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of it, and not to hearken to the Call of God to a more full and Through Reformation. And it will be very hard
<pb facs="tcp:154250:13"/> for the first Adventurers herein to Stem the Tide and Current of the Popular Vogue and Cry against them, to be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fam'd and condemn'd by the Generality; and even by Good Men, though not able to discern what They do; and to come in earnest to deny and forsake all for Christ. Yet such Hero's there will be, who shall break through all, and generously bear their Testimony: who shall in spight of all Temporal Regards openly Profess and Own the Dispensation of the Spirit in its <hi>Infancy.</hi> To such the Call is now gone forth; and chiefly to those that are the Head Shepherds and Pastors of the Flock of Christ, as most capable, and also most concern'd to look out for and discern the <hi>Day</hi> of their Visitation. That they may behold with Joy that the Fields are already White unto the Harvest; and may themselves, being Anointed by the true Spirit of God, be sent forth as <hi>Angel-Reapers:</hi> and Experience a more full and Blessed Effect of their Ministry and Labours. Happy they who shall be Early engaged in this Vintage of God, these shall enjoy all the high and peculiar Prero<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gatives
<pb facs="tcp:154250:13"/> of the <hi>First-Born:</hi> and in this great Opportunity shall with St. <hi>Paul</hi> work out for themselves a Crown of Innumerable Converts, which are to be as the Subjects of their future King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom; their Joy and Glory for ever. To these in an especial manner belongs that Prophecy, <hi>Dan. 12.3. They that be Wise</hi> [or Teachers] <hi>shall shine as the Brightness of the Firmament, and They that Turn many to Righteousness as the Stars for ever and ever.</hi> So let the true Labourers in Thy Harvest; go forth, O God, even the <hi>Messengers</hi> of Thy Kingdom: and let Truth and Judgmen<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> go before Them unto Victory. So let Thy Kingdom come: and let Thy Will be done; even here upon Earth, as it is in Heaven:</p>
            <closer>Amen.</closer>
            <closer>HALLELƲJAH.</closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:14"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:154250:14"/>
            <head>
               <hi>A Third Message</hi> To the Philadelphian Society.</head>
            <p>WHereas there have been Two Messages already given forth to the <hi>Philadelphian Society,</hi> there has been a mighty Strong enkindling from the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven Spirits before the Throne of God and the Lamb for the send<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing forth a Third; giving no rest, but Ecchoing Night and Day till the Angel-Heralds shall go forth as Embassadors from the Prince of all Kings both of the Upper and Nether Worlds: which are known and Nominated in the Eternal Counsel and Wisdom of
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:154250:15"/> the Father; being Seven bright Morning Stars, that shall go be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Seven Shepherds that raised shall be in Conjunction with them, Personating the great and mighty Kingly Shepherd Christ the Lord, by his giving them a Commission, Power and Authority to Sound a new Alarum for the Gathering in and making up a true <hi>Phila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delphian</hi> Fold; which are yet scat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter'd throughout all Nations to the utmost ends of the Earth.</p>
            <p>Love, Good-will, Grace, and Peace from the God and Father of the whole Creation, and from him that is the first begotten of the New Creation; and from the Comforter that does reveal and open the great Mystery and Love of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Eternal Wisdom, to the Seven Churches in <hi>England:</hi> and generally to the Seven Churches
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:154250:15"/> throughout the World disperst, as <hi>first,</hi> the Ancient Church of the <hi>Jews,</hi> that was, and is not, and is to be. 2. The <hi>Roman</hi> Church. 3. The <hi>Greek</hi> 4. The <hi>Aethiopian.</hi> 5. The <hi>Lutheran.</hi> 6. The <hi>French</hi>-Reformed, or <hi>Calvinistical.</hi> 7. The Ancient Church of the <hi>Valleys.</hi> An In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitation to you all from the great Head-Shepherd, is, to fly out of the confusion of <hi>Babylon,</hi> and to come under the orderly and peaceable Government of the <hi>Sion</hi> Kingdom: where no Strife nor Contention is known, but where Truth and Righteousness, and Love, are the only Ruling Law. Then this was cryed in the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Heavens of the mind, Be no longer silent, nor slack to go forth to declare and make known what further relates to the Call of these Churches. For this is the
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:154250:16"/> Great and Notable Day, as be<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>longing to this Age, wherein th<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> great and mighty Angel of the Co<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>venant hath in verity said, that h<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> will not suffer his Flocks that ar<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> to make up the <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Church to lie slumbering in thei<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> Formalities any longer. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he has commissionated his Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven Angels to go forth to blow their Horns, to awaken such as have a Name to live, &amp; yet are deaf &amp; dead, because the <hi>life</hi> had not been freely accepted &amp; entertain'd by them: but the Love of the Eter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Father does so strongly and vehemently burn in the Heart of the beloved Son, as therefrom to cast forth the living sparkling Powers, conveyable through the Holy Ghost, to enlighten and Inspire where the Cloud of dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness and deadness had overspread. For Love-Violence shall overtake
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:154250:16"/> to bring the backsliding Churches <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>nto their own Native Country <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>nd Land. And by a terrible and outstretched Arm this gathering will be: according to the wise <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ethod, way and manner of <gap reason="illegible: left margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>he great <hi>Alpha</hi> and <hi>Omega</hi>'s pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding: as he hath given forth the Description unto the inseeing mind, by way of figurative Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>presentation, according to what is here declared.</p>
            <p>The pure Heavenly Element opening, gave the sight of the high <hi>Emanuel</hi> King, encompassed with Myriads of Angels, that were said to be the Virgin-Church of the first-born Fruits, that make up the beginning of the New Creation. The behold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of which was so amazing, that it put a stop and suspension to all of the mortal part. But there was an hovering and over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>shadowing
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:154250:17"/> presence that gave strength both to see and hea<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> what the design of this great Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sitation and Love-Emanation was which was related and referred to this whole visible Creation. After this discovery, it was mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved to enquire what this great Appearance did signifie, and it was Answer'd, that according to this Pattern in the Heavens, such a <hi>Jerusalem</hi> was to be prepared here upon the Earth. Then it was queried further in the Spirit of the mind, by what way and means shall such a Redemption be wrought out here in this low<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er World. Then was it opened to be, that as there was a Flood of Water that drowned the Old World, wherein was all the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bomination and Venom of Sin, whereby the Creator was bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dened and wearied: So also he
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:154250:17"/> is at this day, for the oppression and cries of the Groaning Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion: and therefore as it has been decreed, so now it is pronounced that a New thing God is about to do, which is by open<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing (in another manner) the Win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dows of Heaven, and breaking up the Deeps below; that so the Waters of Life from thence might flow, for the covering and drowning the Earthly part in Man, fulfilling that Prophecy hereby, <hi>The Glorious Lord shall be a place of broad Waters.</hi> which shall rise as the Waters of the Sanctuary, till to that height as to be an overwhelming. This was said to be a Baptiz<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ng River, wherein the healing Virtue should be for the Cure of all that had been infected by the Poison and Venom of the Serpent.</p>
            <p>All this is to be the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>runner
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:154250:18"/> to make way for that New Creation-World prophesied of, which is to be expected and hoped for. Some Footsteps where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of are already taken, in order to i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s Entrance: for the Spirit of Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phecy has in some declared that from the Year 1697. to 1700. a good Progress will be made; and from thence it will proceed and increase till it comes to the Seventh Thousand Years Sabbath, answering to the Seventh Day of Rest from the Creation. In the Compass of this time, great and wonderful Revolutions will be; and are already begun by the Spirits breaking forth. Which as yet is but the Light of one Day; but this one shall multiply, till it come to be as the Light of Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven Days: and then our Sun of Glory shall no more set, nor the Spirit withdraw its self, as it has
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:154250:18"/> done since the Apostles Days; for in that Age it was only as a sudden Shower, in comparison of the Remainders that are to be poured forth in the latter Age. Wherein the New Modelled World, over which Christ shall Reign as a mighty Monarch, shall be made manifest. But it may be queried, what method or way shall be taken for the bringing these Prophecies to pass, there being so little yet appearing in Order hereunto, the Babylonish Confusion still Reigning, and such Divisions among the nominated Churches by their taking up the Spiritual Weapons of War, and piercing and wounding each other? The which Grievances have been spread, and lamented by such as are quickned into the Birth of Love. Upon which An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swer was given from the Throne-Seat
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:154250:19"/> of Love, that these rend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings and dividings were taken such knowledge of, and had so pierced the Heart of him who is to be Heir and Restorer of all Nations, that he would now raise up Messengers and Pastors, whom he would make as Vials to pour in his all-Saving and Healing Name: And as the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer Ministration went forth in the Washing of Regeneration, by <hi>John</hi> the <hi>Baptist,</hi> who was a Type in his Day; So now again the Spirit of <hi>John</hi> the <hi>Evangelist</hi> is to rise and be the Forerunner of the Ministration of the Love, and to make ready the <hi>Philadelphia</hi> Bride, whose adorning and co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vering will be by the Flaming Sun of Love; by waiting in the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of Love for her Bridegroom in his Glorified Person to her to appear. Now then give ear and
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:154250:19"/> hearken to the Spirit's Voice, from the Mighty King and Shep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herd that stands charged with all the Flocks that are to make the Virgin-Body: to you this Message is sent, who Pastors are of the Churches of this Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, what Nomination or Title soever ye bear, be it known to you, that your Commission is to go forth first to Baptize with the Water of Life, not according to the deadness of the Letter, but by the Internal conveyance of the Life-quickning Power, that may give Sin its deaths wound; and this in Order to a higher de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree of Baptism, which is from the Glassy Sea (wherein is the Holy Fire mingled, and co-ope<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rating with the Water) which is the Ministry of the Holy Ghost, which requires a true Examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:154250:20"/> of those that are called here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto, whereby it may be known that they have the Right Mission.</p>
            <p>For the Confirmation of this there was shewn to me a Descending Angel, coming down from the Glassy Sea, with a Pair of Golden Balances in his Hand, uttering this Voice, All must be tryed and weighed, who through these Baptisms are to pass; that they be as live Coals or Burning Sapphires: such as appeared in the one Scale; and were to answer to a Golden Weight in the other. For it was cryed by the Angel, Thus it is absolutely necessary that those Fire-Stones that are to be gather<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to make up the Virgin-Bride, must be found answerable to their Glorified Head. Accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to this Rule therefore mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sures are to be taken for degrees
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:154250:20"/> and growths in Stature, till they come up to this full Weight. Then was there a Roll shown me in the Hand of the same Angel, the Writing whereof shined like Gold, giving the Characters and Rules whereby it might be known who are of the true <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Church, that they might be di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stinguished from those that should take up that Name and Title for a Covering. Who are to be try<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by what was there exprest.</p>
            <p>The first was the bearing the Dying-Mark or Crucifixion to the Degenerated Birth: in a most deep sence, deploring its Lapse and Apostacy from its original pure state, Renouncing the Earthly born Life and worldly Principle, quite sinking away by Abnegation and Annihila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion herefrom being thus Buri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with Christ in Death, we are
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:154250:21"/> taught to lie in the Passive Grave in Silence, till the Lord the Quickning Spirit shall descend to become a Life quickning Birth, whereby a new Creaturely For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation is brought forth, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Nature of the Divine Humanity of Christ: which will gradually spring and grow in eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry such one, till they come to be as full grown Trees of Life to replenish the New Earth and Heavens.</p>
            <p>For the further proving and tryal of this renewed State, it will be known by the Effects and Fruits that will accompany it. There will be a Renewing and finding of that which was lost in the First <hi>Paradise,</hi> answerable to every part of the Lapse and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pravation. For as the first <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dam</hi> by finding Himself, that is by Introducing the selfish Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perties
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:154250:21"/> through the Serpent's sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tilty, lost God out of himself; so that he became naked, and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>potent, being uncloathed of the Garment of Purity, Power and Dominion, and turn'd from the Angelical to a Terrestrial Form; all his Off-spring became the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plorable Image of it: so there is no way for the Recovery of this, and to find God again, but by Undoing all this, and through the Death to this outward Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciple by the Power of the Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting Word, he drawing himself as a living draught upon all that gives a new Birth from the Dead, being Restored again to all the same Supercelestial Dignifications by the God-man. Now Christ being the First Fruits of a New Generation, does multiply him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>self through the Virgin-Wisdom: that the Degrees of God may be
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:154250:22"/> therein fulfilled. Running Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rallel with the first <hi>Adam</hi> tha<gap reason="illegible: right margin cropped or obscured" resp="#murp" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> was planted in <hi>Paradise;</hi> who had his Virgin in himself, and should have brought forth a God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like Off-spring; but that he turn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed his Eye from the Divine Es<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sential Virgin within himself to speculate the Outward Creation, and so his desire being captivated therein, he fell into a slumber, losing thereby the Supercelestial Element and his true Virgin; so that God saw it necessary to give him a Terrestrial help. Thro' which all low mortal Births have sprung forth, which a Death (at least) Mystical must pass upon, till the Second <hi>Adam,</hi> which is the Lord from Heaven in a new Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciple of Light and Life, shall put forth as a Paradisical Plant again by a renewed Virgin-Generation: that shall be out of all danger
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:154250:22"/> of being defl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ured. Because it is secured as being now no more twain, but one Spirit with God and the Lamb: so fast tied in this Matrimonial Union, as that no subtlety or wiles of the Serpent and all his Hierarchy shall ever nullifie or make void. For the Paradisical Property which was in Locality, no place for it is found: but the Inward and My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stical rising from another Fund or Ground shall remain Inviola<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble; as arched about with fla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming Seraphims for a glorious defence. Wherein Inclosed is the Second <hi>Adam</hi> with his Vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gin Spouse, the Eternal Wisdom, who without any molestation shall bring forth the Children of the New Creation: so multiply<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and replenishing the New Earth and Heavens, <hi>Gen.</hi> 1.28. <hi>Rev.</hi> 21.1. To these new model<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:154250:23"/> and God-formed Creatures, the lost and disappeared Angeli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal Image, with Soveraignty and dominion shall be Restored again. Then that saying tho from an Apostatized Angel will be made good a better way: that they shall be as Gods knowing good and evil. Looking into and understanding the Root in which the evil Property was ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifested, without breaking the Harmony, or permitting it to go out of its Order; but reigning over all the dark Regions and Worlds in a God-like Supre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>macy.</p>
            <p>This is set forth in the first place to all Pastors and People here in <hi>England,</hi> that as in a Glass you may come to see the most Glorious Restitution, which is designed by the <hi>Alpha</hi> and <hi>Omega:</hi> whereby he will bring
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:154250:23"/> forth himself in his Bridal Church, that shall be all comely without Spot or Blemish as the White Stone upon which shall be written, The Lord our Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teousness, or <hi>Jehovah Shammah</hi> dwelleth here, as in his own glorious City, compact and made up of <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Inhabitants.</p>
            <p>Now it may be queried, Whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther such a <hi>Philadelphian</hi> State may be expected, or be in any measure begun in this Age?</p>
            <p>In Answer hereunto; the Sower is already gone forth, that hath cast into the Earth such Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving Sparks of Light, in order to that great Harvest that must bring forth these Golden Sheaves that shall be offered upon the Flaming Altar: where nothing can suffer loss but the Straw and Chaff hanging about them. It will be said perhaps, what ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearance
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:154250:24"/> is there of any such thing; because so much of the Thorny Ground is every where upon the faceof the Earth spread, that should seem to choak and stifle this Grain? Too deplo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rably true it is, but the Day is come, and still breaking, for the Spirit of Judgment and Burning to pass through, for Refining and Purging the Inward Floor in Man, and Nature; as that fiery Leaven that shall be the Transmuting Stone to the gross Metal, changing it into the <hi>Ophir</hi> Gold, according to that Scripture, <hi>A Man shall be as the Gold of</hi> Ophir. But the beginning of this will be very small, weak and despiseable, threatned with many tempestu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Storms, to stagger the First puttings forth of this New Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation; according to that Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phecy of the <hi>Psalmist, There shall
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:154250:24"/> be an Handful of Corn in the Earth; upon the top of the Mountains. The Fruit thereof shall shake like</hi> Lebanon: <hi>and they of the City shall flourish like the Grass of the Earth,</hi> Psal. 72.16. So that out of this Stem and Root of <hi>Jesse</hi> shall a mighty Increase be, till a City there be all compact of Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious Stones, that shall send forth their sparkling Radiancy, reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vering the lost Virgin-Purity, and flourishing in the Rosie-<hi>Sharon</hi>-Beauty, mingled with the Lilly White and Brightness. For so it becometh the Bride of the Lamb to appear in this Transparency. This is what in general is repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sented in the clear Mirror of Wis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom's Glass, that such a new sown Crop will come forth, and even in this latter day appear.</p>
            <p>But methinks it is cryed in my Ear; <hi>Shew it us more particularly
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:154250:25"/> after what Model this must be, whereby we may yet better know the Character of this true</hi> Phila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delphian <hi>State, that no counter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit or deceiveable Spirit may cloath themselves with the Name, without the Essential Body of it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now then to give forth the unquestionable Signs and Descrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, we must define their Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vity and Birth, which is no less than from the Godhead it self, bringing them forth through the Womb of Eternal Virgin Nature, conceived within the human Form and Vehicle; and so gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dually in all Internal Spiritual Members it comes to be quick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned to a Spiritual Body, within the Outward Body: which is as the Husk that covers and hides it from the gross and vulgar Eye; and not only so, but in many for some<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time it is unknown to themselves,
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:154250:25"/> by reason of the Predominancy of the degenerated outward Birth, till the Supersensual be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gins to arise stronger and more powerful than the outward, and so proceed conquering and sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duing it, and working out the gross Elementary part, till it come to a perfect Annihilation. It will be then asked, if that be that mark of a perfect <hi>Philadelphian,</hi> who can hope or believe to ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rive thereto? It is so strait that few there are that can pass thro' it. But let it not be counted Impossible; because Christ the Lord will be both the Way and the Door of Entrance: who would never have propounded and excited to it, but that he well knew where the Power of sufficiency did rest, for the ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>complishment of it by Incorpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rating himself within them after
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:154250:26"/> a high and spiritual manner; and then this pure and perfect thing growing up, will make it all easie and natural, to live, move and act in Deiformity.</p>
            <p>Now hereby all are to seek whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther their Birth be from Above, even from the God of Love. For the true <hi>Philadelphian</hi> State con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sisteth altogether of such an Es<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sential Birth of Love, as no place is found for Enmity, Envyings, Malice, Hatred, evil Surmizings, Jealousie, Fear &amp; Unbelief. These all be the Fruits of the Evil Tree that must wither and dye out of Natures property. Now opposite to this Will-Tree, when it shall be rooted up, then place is found for the Tree of Life and Love to grow and flourish out of the new refined Earth: which is laden with all precious Fruits as the Golden Apples of Love,
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:154250:26"/> whose drops do distil so sweetly, as to melt and dissolve all remain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders of those bitter fruits which from Death's Tree did spring. Now from hence it may be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected that out of the new Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>radisical Mould, the choice and precious Minerals from the deep Mines will be broken up: So that what lay under a dark Face of covering in Natures ground, by the bright lustre of the Love Fire-stones, shall be brought to light. From whence shall Spring that true Charity and Love that think<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth no evil, beareth all things, believeth all things, hopeth the best, and is not easily provoked, or offended at any thing that thwarts or crosses it. It lives a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove all Mutations proceeding from temporary things, so as you cannot put it out of this even
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:154250:27"/> and divine Temperature of mind.</p>
            <p>Now from this deep grounded Birth of Love that Faith will al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so put forth, and work in such a Conquering degree, as will sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>due all that in a lasped degene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racy hath had its Dominion, throughout all of man's old Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion: by and through which an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other Kingdom will break forth, consisting of Wisdom, Purity, Po<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ency and Might. So that the nakedness of the first <hi>Adam</hi> (in us) in its shame will be thus cloathed upon; recovering its Dominion by the Reign of the Second <hi>Adam</hi> the Lord from Heaven, descending into Nature again, to act, and perform, what to his own Resurrection-Life does, through his chosen Vessels, belong. Which consist<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:154250:27"/> in such a high Unity of Faith, as that whatever shall be willed and decreed by this Spirit here below, shall be established in the Heavens: For this is that Gol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den Key that will open for the <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Flock, that Gate that shall enter them into the <hi>Lebanon</hi> Glory. Where they shall have power to bind and to loose, to open and shut. Here the Prerogative-Royal will be given to do all miraculous Won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, as Christ himself did, who said, <hi>Greater Works then these shall ye do.</hi> So that the lost Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stolical Gifts will return and flow again as from their own Fountain; the possibility here will be to have power over Death and Mortality, recover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing languishing Nature, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving the Understanding opened to comprehend the pure Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guage
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:154250:28"/> of Nature; and to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce out of all Confusion of Tongues to the one pure and Angelical Speech. 'Tis not to be numbred or expressed what may be done by this Faith that does operate from the Birth of Love.</p>
            <p>Now hearken and hear, all ye from the highest degrees and Dignity, whether of Order Temporal or Ecclesiastical, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scending from the greatest to the least, whether <hi>Jew</hi> or <hi>Gentile,</hi> Bond or Free. To you this Message is sent through and by the Embassadour of Love, who has received the Vial of Golden Oyl of Love to pour forth, that if possible it may heal what the Scorpion Spirit has gone forth to wound every where, by rend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from this Love-Principle; and opening the wrathful and
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:154250:28"/> Satanical Kingdom, which the <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Kingdom of the Love shall be able to shut up.</p>
            <p>O what greater Motives can we present to gain upon the dark unbelieving and averse Spirit stir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring in this present Generation, than these great Immunities that are intailed upon the true <hi>Phila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delphian</hi> Worthies, the Virgin-Church of the First-born: that is to be made the New <hi>Jerusa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lem</hi>-City; bright and glorious not only within, but also with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out, compact and made up of Oriental Stones, and adorned to be the Bride of God and the Lamb, out of which will spring that Kingly Birth that shall the Everlasting Reign set up in Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty, Power and Dominion, in the midst of his <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Flock.</p>
            <pb n="30" facs="tcp:154250:29"/>
            <p>Now a Cry from the Heavens does go forth; who shall be those Angels of all the several Churches of this Nation, that shall go out as Trumpets for the Awakening the Sleepy <hi>Laodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceans</hi> that in a Lukewarm tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per do yet remain to come out of their Traditions and Forma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lities, Confusions and Divisions, into the Unity of the <hi>Philadel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phian</hi> Love. Who among the true enlightned wise and seri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous minded, would not be Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitious of this high Honour, to be Principal Shepherds, having the Golden Crook of Love to hook and gather into the Fold of the Great Shepherd; where a Feed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing shall be upon the <hi>Lebanon</hi> Fruits that will Spirit Life and Power every day renew? O <hi>England, England,</hi> know the Day of thy Visitation, for a
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:154250:29"/> wonderful Morning-Light is springing. Therefore open the Windows of thy Mind and let it in, for then it will usher in the Lord of Glory: who hath said, Behold I come to Reign in Love's Kingdom. So let all who this Message shall hear, cry with one Heart, Let thy Kingdom thus come in Peace and Amity.</p>
            <p>But now the <hi>Alpha</hi> and <hi>Om<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>g<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> does send forth a second Cry to the seven more general and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mote Churches, to you also the Fountain deep of God's Love does Flow. The Angels of the Love are commissionated and flying towards you, declaring that there is a Pool whereunto you are invited to enter in, for healing all of the Sick and lapsed Nature.</p>
            <p>Now to you first of the <hi>Roman</hi> Church, who plead your Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quity
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:154250:30"/> and Succession from the Apostolical Fountain: Cauti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned and counselled you are to try whether your T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>tle hereunto by your Practice and Conformity thereto can be made good. For know there is a Fiery Law gone forth out of the Mouth of the Great Apostle of our Profes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion Christ Jesus: yea a Spirit of Burning and Judgment, to try both your Ways, Works &amp; Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ships. So that whatever is found Light that cannot Balance the Golden Grain, and whatever is superfluous and drossy, you must expect will be devoured by the fervent heat of God's Love Jealousie. Therefore a Call is to you that ye may recover your first and Primitive State. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it appertains Principally to him who has taken the Chair of Ruling Power over this Church,
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:154250:30"/> as the Representative Head, to examine and prove whether he has the true Mission: which only can be known by the Power and Spirit of Jesus in Him. In whose Hand is the Golden Key to open the Kingdom of Love, Unity, and Peace: For the Gathering in of the <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Flock. Thus he may become a true Shep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herd and Overseer of such as may make up the Virgin-Church. Let it be known to you from the <hi>Alpha</hi> and <hi>Omega,</hi> that Titles, and Words, and Forms, will not pass through the Fiery Judgment: therefore Return, Return; and strengthen that which is ready to dye; of the more inward and Spiritual Life among you; and Recover your first Love, that you may bear the Right Mark and Character of the <hi>Philadel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phian</hi>-Bride. This receive as a true
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:154250:31"/> Message and Call from Him that is All in All.</p>
            <p>Now to you of the <hi>Lutheran</hi> Church, and the rest of the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed Churches, the Word of Wisdom and Counsel is, that ye do not think it sufficient that ye have in some degree broke thro' the night of Darkness and Igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance in the Beginnings of a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation. For ye are not to stint and bind up your selves here to the first Dawning of the Day, because the true Oily Lamp will burn brighter and brighter, till it comes to that Unity of Love and Charity, that admits of no Rupture or Division; and till all that harsh and severe Fire of the <hi>Elias</hi> Ministration, (wherein your first Reformation went forth to prepare the way for a greater and higher to come after it,) shall be swallowed up in the following
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:154250:31"/> Dispensation of the Love. Therefore now it behoveth you, and chiefly the Head Shepherds that stand charged with the Flocks of Christ, to cast your Eye back upon the Purity, Love and Zeal of the Infancy, or first goings forth of your Churches; and to compare and try your Lamps hereby whether they have advanced in Light, and in the Power of Practical Holiness; or whether they have not rather declined and burnt dimmer: and how far what opened in Spirit and Life, is sunk in deadness and Formality. Therefore each one of you are to turn inward, and there call to your Well of Salva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to Spring and make as a fruitful <hi>Lebanon,</hi> that the King of Love and Peace may walk a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong you, and Seal you with the <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Seal; which is the
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:154250:32"/> Flaming Heart of Love and Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty: slight not, nor reject this Message that comes from Him that dwelleth in Loves Burning Bush. Whither he invites you all of the Reformed Churches Universally to come, and Drink of the Inspiring Cup, the Wine of which makes you Ministers of the Spirit, to go forth as Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bassadors of Reconciliation, which will be your Crown, Joy, and Glory. Thus you are now Summon'd both Pastors and Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple of all Churches to examine and prove in your Selves, whether you bear the Right Character of the Churche and Spouse of Christ, for the Princely Bride<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>groom is now expecting such a high Degree of Reformation in such an Uniformity as shall trans<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cend all Literal and Dead Forms that will not bear the Touch of
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:154250:32"/> the Divine and Burning Stone of Love. Therefore as you de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sire and long for his second Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearance, and Kingdom spread<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in its Power and Glory here upon Earth, be watching in the Inward Court of a pure and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect Heart and Mind, listning to hear the Voice of your Kingly Shepherd calling you forth to make up one intire Fold; where he may go in and out among you, leading you to living Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tains and fresh Pastures, that no more Drought or Famine may be known: the Essential Word springing from the Root-Essence of your own Souls, whereby in the Ministration of the Holy Ghost, you may be Seal'd and Sign'd by the the Alpha and Omega, to whom all the Churches are to be joyned as one; Crowned with the Everlasting Diadem, for
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:154250:33"/> Praise, Renown, and Glory to him, who was, is, and is to come, <hi>Amen.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Hear also O ye <hi>Greeks,</hi> and come from Afar, even from the <hi>East,</hi> and from the <hi>North:</hi> And give Ear, O thou <hi>Ethiopia,</hi> that wast heretofore, and art still be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loved of the Lord thy God. O <hi>Ethiopia</hi> make haste and prepare thy Chariots: for there is an A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larm gone forth from the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vens. Fly ye apace, rest not, but obey this Call that goeth forth from your Angel, standing before the Throne of the migh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Priestly King, and inviting you to hasten away, and behold the Glory of <hi>Solomons</hi> Rising Day, that is now approaching upon the Earth. Let therefore the Princes of <hi>Saba</hi> and <hi>Sheba</hi> bring their Gifts. O come ye from the <hi>South,</hi> the Voice saith:
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:154250:33"/> and let Offerings of Myrrh, of Incense, and of Gold, be presen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to this Great King of <hi>Peace</hi> who is to Rule all Nations with Righteousness and with a Spirit of Love Meekness, &amp; to confound those that delight in War; by tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning their Swords into Sickles. For the South Wind shall blow a sweet Gale: and the Boisterous <hi>Euroclydon</hi> shall be appeased in its Furious Might, so that the <hi>Ark of Faith</hi> may ride <hi>safe</hi> upon the Waters, without danger of a Wrack: and the Prince, who has set up his Throne <hi>in the sides of the North,</hi> being there by the <hi>Michael</hi>-Art confin'd, shall not be able to unbind the <hi>North</hi> Wind any more: or to teach the Nations to destroy one ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther.</p>
            <pb n="40" facs="tcp:154250:34"/>
            <p>Behold the Angel of <hi>Grecia</hi> is gone out, not to Fight, but to proclaim Peace: and to sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon in his Captives from the Land of the <hi>Aliens</hi> and <hi>Barba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rians.</hi> Awaken, O ye <hi>Grecians,</hi> and sleep not: Awake also, <hi>O ye Ethiopians,</hi> and let not Slum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber longer seem upon you. For the <hi>Night</hi> of the Apostacy is now drawing to an End, and the <hi>Day</hi> is at Hand, which all your Fore-fathers who received the Faith did expect to see, and do yet press after, that it may ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear to you their Off-spring. Wherefore remember your first Works, and look back to the Days of Old; before ye forgot your Espousals, and the Love of your Youth. Remember, saith the Spirit, what was Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ently said to the Churches in Thee: and let every one that
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:154250:34"/> hath an Ear, hear also what the Spirit still saith to the Churches, <hi>Behold, I come Quickly, as a Thief in the Night: Watch there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, and do thy first Works.</hi> Therefore let all the Churches in <hi>Asia</hi> listen, wait, and return to the Lord their Mighty Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deemer, who hath wounded them for their Transgressions; but will turn again unto them, and heal them for his Names Sake.</p>
            <p>And as for thee, O little Flock of the Valleys, who hast not been afraid to bear a Testimony for thy God, neither hast deny'd the Word of the Patience of thy Jesus: he calleth now unto thee, and saith, Lo! I stand at the Door, and will reward all thy Works, and what thou hast suffer'd for My Names sake. Wherefore Arise and Shine all
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:154250:35"/> ye who have lain in the Dust: for though ye have been cast out <hi>among the Pots,</hi> yet an An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gel Messenger is descending, that he may give unto you the Golden Wings <hi>of the Dove.</hi> Be strong then, knowing that your Salvation is nigh, if ye Believe.</p>
            <p>Now an Invitation and Call is from the God of <hi>Abraham</hi> to you, who are his Off-spring, tho scatter'd and dispersed into all Nations, as Branches that have been for a time Broken off from your true Root. Return, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn O Back sl ding <hi>Israel,</hi> and see how many Generations are now passed over, wherein you have not known the Day of your Visitation. But let not ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Age of Time pass over you, before you Own and Confess the Great and Mighty saving Name Jesus. Whom though
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:154250:35"/> you have denyed in his first Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearance in Flesh, yet his Grace to you does so super-abound with all Bowels of Compassion, whereby Forgiveness of your Unbelief may work you to a kind Repentance and Remorse. There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore charged ye be not to neglect your time any longer, but to come out of your dead Ceremonies, Traditions and Types: and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derstands what lies under the Vail of these Shadows, that Christ the Substance of all may be revealed in you, and that you may understand and know the many Prophecies that are to have their Fulfilling for your Restoration. Such as <hi>Ezek.</hi> 36.24. &amp;c. For I will take you from among the Heathen, and gather you out of all Countries, and bring you into your own Land. Then will I sprinkle clean Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:154250:36"/> upon you, &amp;c. A new Heart also will I give you, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And I will put my Spirit within you, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> But yet <hi>Verse</hi> 37. I will for this be enquired of by the House of <hi>Israel,</hi> to do it for them. So that you see your Call and Duty. Which is to cease from laying such a stress upon your Literal Law, and to make no longer an Idol of it; for that Ministration, though Great and Glorious in its time, must give way to a higher: which is the Law of the Sp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rit of Life in Christ, (who can only make you Free) as it is engraven upon your Hearts. This is the true Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumcision of the Spirit which takes away the Blindness of your Minds: O that the true Guiding Star Christ, may now arise with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in you, to prepare you for his Second Coming in his Kingdom,
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:154250:36"/> in Great Power and Glory. Who only waits till you be brought in to the Belief and Love of Him as your King and Saviour. And now sends from his Throne a Mighty Angel to sound forth his Trumpet unto you, O House of <hi>Israel;</hi> and to all the Tribes near and afar off, every where: that you may hear the Voice of your True Shepherd, calling you to be joyned among the rest of these Churches mention'd, and to make up one Fold with them. What does the Voice Cry, but Awake, Awake, O slumbring Seed of <hi>Jacob,</hi> and make no Lingring nor Delay; for hereby you do retard not only your own Joy and Felicity in the Peaceable Kingdom, that is now in Expectation, but also that of the whole Body besides belonging to Christ the Head. Therefore in the Love and Bowels of God
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:154250:37"/> the Eternal Father, and with the Open Arms of that Jesus, whom you and your Fore-fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers have Ignorantly Despised and Rejected, you are Intreated and Besought to receive and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertain this Love-Message of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conciliation: so referring you to the true Oracle of the Spirit and Tabernacle of God, open<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing within you, as that Living Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stimony, that Rends away all Vails that are before it; Even so, let all Knees bow, confess, and own Him, who is made Manifest for the Salvation of all Nations.</p>
            <p>There is another Cry also goes forth to you of the Turkish Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narchy. How long, how long will you lye in your Dark Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, rejecting that Light of Christ, which was once made Manifest in the Flesh, and is Now again to be Reveal'd in Spirit, as Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>running
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:154250:37"/> his Glorious Appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance. Behold to you also, is the Golden Crook of Love held out, yea to all People, Nations, and Languages; even of the Heathens that have not known God. All which have Now their Call to come from the utmost Parts of the Earth, to the Bright<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness of this Day Break; for the Gospel of Everlasting Peace and Good Will does Greet you all: And though to many it has not come to the Outward Ear, yet the Original Book may open within you. For the Age of Time is come about, wherein the whole Earth shall be filled with the Knowledge of the Lord, by the Inundation of the Spirit, as the Living Waters that shall cover the Dead and dark Earth of Man's depraved Nature. Which through the Baptism of Fire and
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:154250:38"/> Water, must come to be renew'd For the <hi>Amen</hi> Saith, Behold I come to make all things New: even so, let all these Churches Acquiesces with one Voice, to the Yea and <hi>Amen.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>There is yet a louder Cry and Trumpet Sound from out of the Throne of God, and the Lamb to the Kingly Monarchs that here upon this lower Earth do Reign. More Principally to him who sits at the Helm of Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in this Nation. Consider, <hi>O King,</hi> by what a wonderful <hi>Hand</hi> you have been brought in, and planted here: and recollect for what <hi>End</hi> the Key of the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment of these Nations has been intrusted into Your Hands. And for what Special <hi>Work</hi> you may be design'd by Providence. And as a Signal Appearance of God, has been manifested for
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:154250:38"/> your Preservation, and for the maintaining still to you the Scep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, that it could not be pluck'd away. What is now requir'd of You, but to sway it, as another <hi>David</hi> in Righteousness and Truth, by judging the Poor of the People, by saving the Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of the Needy, and break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in pieces the Oppressors. Which may, as after the end of his Wars, introduce the true <hi>So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lomon</hi>'s Reign in Tranquility; whereby all the present Divisi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons may be brought into a Bles<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed Harmony and Unity. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto you have already made some Advance, and bent your Force to a Reconciliation of the divided Parties among Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stants, by opening a Door of true Christian and Native Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; whereby the Thrones of Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces are Establish'd in the Hearts
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:154250:39"/> of their Subjects. And let the other Monarchs of the Earth, and Soveraign Princes, that have not yet reach'd to such a Free and Disinterested Spirit, but stand more bound up to their own Sentiments, and such a particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar mode of Worship, learn from such a President how to Establish themselves, under the Throne of the most High God and King. Go on in this great Latitude U<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niversality of Love, under the great and Mighty Shepherd Christ Jesus, to bring in all the scatter'd and divided Flocks into one Fold to feed upon that Pasture that putteth forth only the sweet scented Flowers of Love.</p>
            <p>O that it might be put not only into the Heart of one, but also of all other Kings, Poten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tates, and States. What a migh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Over-turn would it make, of
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:154250:39"/> the Babylonish Strife and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fusion, That is spread over the Earth, if the Great Ones that are Invested with Power, would imploy all their Force and Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority for the Propogation of this Kingdom, which over all the Kingdoms of the Earth, is to Reign. Therefore Consider, and receive it as a Charge and Command, all you who do Reign in Subordination to him; and know that the Prophetical Time is now come, wherein God will Anoint you with the Pouring out of his Holy Spirit upon you, to make you true Kings, Priests and Prophets of the Heavenly Order, that you may become Nursing Fathers, and Nursing Mothers to his Church. By this a hopeful Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pectation will be of a full and Thorough Reformation for the
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:154250:40"/> bringing in of the New Creati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Glory, whereby the Taber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nacle of God will descend to rest in great Splendor and Glory upon the Earth. <hi>Amen.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Thus I have concluded my Message in all Faithfulness ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Command given, hoping a Blessed Issue, which is the fullness of all Blessings to come upon all Nations. And in the mean time I stand in my Lot, according to the Council and Decree of Him who will ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fill all Prophesies Past and Present.</p>
            <div type="chacteristics_of_a_Philadelphian">
               <head>The Marks of a <hi>True Philadelphi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an,</hi> according to the Descrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the Blessed Apostle St. <hi>PAƲL.</hi>
               </head>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian Suffereth Long.]</head>
                  <p>THE first Victory of the True <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Heroe may be said to consist properly
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:154250:40"/> in Suppressing the <hi>Irascible</hi> Emo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions of the Soul: or in stop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping the Mouth of that Roaring Lyon, which watches all the Travellers to the City of Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therly Love, how he may sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prize and devour them. For the two Great <hi>Boanerges;</hi> the most Beloved Brothers had like to have fallen into the Jaws of this Lyon: and the most Mas<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culine Champion of Christ, and most Zealous of all his Disci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples was Bit by him, and had much ado to escape with his Life. Wherefore having these Examples set before him, he is exceeding Cautions to Guard himself against this Wild and Furious Beast. And he strives to Imitate the Long Suffering and Patience of the Deity to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards Evil Doers. He studies to Conquer his Adversaries with
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:154250:41"/> Love, and to bring them over to him by Kind Offices, or by Presents, as <hi>Jacob</hi> did his Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>Esau.</hi> He is not for calling down Fire from Heaven upon them, or Anathematizing them; but for heaping Coals of Love upon their Heads. He is not for Prosecuting Hereticks or Recusants with the Faggot, or with the Sword: but is for Suf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fering the Tares to grow with the Wheat, till the Day of the <hi>Harvest:</hi> when every ones Work shall be purg'd by Fire.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian is Kind.]</head>
                  <p>AS Courtesie and Kindness is a <hi>Moral</hi> Virtue, so in Him it becomes a <hi>Christian</hi> Grace. Wherefore he cannot be Austere, or Starch'd up to any little For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>malities. His Religion makes him not Soure, or uneasie to
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:154250:41"/> others; but renders him more Sweet, Affable, and Easie, if there be but the least Opportu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity for him hereby of doing a Kind or Generous Office to Any. And though he uses himself much to Solitude and Retirements, with his Blessed Master and Pat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tern; yet whenever he appears in the World, he affects not a Singularity, or to be taken No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice of, but freely converses with it, and Accommodates himself to the Manners of it, so far as Innocently he can. Thus the True <hi>Philadelphian</hi> is the most Obliging Person of the whole World: not only Inoffensive in his Carriage, but even Pleasant, and nobly exe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>cis'd in the most, Advantageous Parts of Human Conversation, as well as the most Delectable. And as diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent as the Address of a Master
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:154250:42"/> of the Ceremonies to a strange Minister, is from that of one Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther to another most intimately Endear'd to him; so is that of this <hi>Philadelphian,</hi> when he converses with Any, from that Outward, Formal, and Ceremo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nial Way which is Practised by the World. In short, none bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter (if so well) understands all the Solid Delights of Conversa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and the permanent Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sures of a True and Masculine Friendship; not Confin'd, but Extended to the very utmost Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacity of his Sphear.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian Envieth not.]</head>
                  <p>WHen he has thus slain the <hi>Lyon</hi> and the <hi>Bear,</hi> he next proceeds to cut off the Head of that most cunning twisting <hi>Serpent</hi> of <hi>Envy,</hi> that would insinuate himself even in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:154250:42"/> Paradise. And it is much more easie to vanquish, subdue, and harmonize the fierce Wrath<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful, and the rough unmannerly Properties of a Disorder'd Soul, then to eradicate this more se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cret and lurking Evil, which lies gnawing on the very Vitals of Religion, in many great and specious Professors. But the True <hi>Philadelphian</hi> is one perfectly Content with that State or Lot, in which he stands, through the Wisdom, Justice and Goodness of God. He thinks not much at any Advantages or Privileges which another doth enjoy: but rather Congratulates them. He is certain that the Master whom he serves, if he be Faithful, will not fail to prefer him: and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he is not at all Sollicitous after any Preferments, Honours, or Riches, which this World can
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:154250:43"/> give, or in the least envies those who possess them. And much less doth he repine at any Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vors confer'd by his Master, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on any of his Fellow-Servants: but is pleas'd thereat. And will not presume to b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd up His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty to Act thus or thus, and to confer his Favours and Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces upon none but those that are of this or that Body, or So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciety, that he likes best. No: he dares not do so: he prefers o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers before himself; thinking himself unworthy of the very least Grace, or Gift of His Holy Spirit bestowed upon him. For,</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian Vaunteth not Himself.]</head>
                  <p>HE will take no Glory or Honour to himself; but will ascribe all to the Supreme Majesty, which he serves, the
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:154250:43"/> Sole Fountain of <hi>Honour,</hi> and the Origine of whatever is <hi>Glorious,</hi> or Praise worthy. He is free therefore from all Ostentation: and being Inconsiderable in his own Eyes, he cannot be Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forward, Temerarious, or Preci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pitate in any Design, but will wait always for the Call and Command of his Master: that so he may not Dishonour, instead of Honouring him. And this al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so teaches him to weigh his Words in the Ballance of the Holy Sanctuary, and not to speak Rashly for God.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian is not puffed up.]</head>
                  <p>FOR he avoids all manner of Ostentation and Imperti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nence, this is a certain Sign that there must be in him somewhat Substantial, and that he is not a Vessel fill'd with Wind. He is
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:154250:44"/> neither Elevated with any Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plause, nor Dejected with Oblo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quy or Contemt. He is contract<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed within a very little Compass, and is not blown up as a Bladder, either with the Vanities and Pomps of the World, or with any Spiritual Attainments, fan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cied or real. But the more he receives, Natural or Supernatu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral, he is still the more Humble, more Passive, and more Resign'd to the Divine Will.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian doth not behave himself Ʋnseemly.]</head>
                  <p>HE takes care to do nothing that is Judecorous: but is a most strict Observer of the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ternal Law of Order. Which Law is the Rule of all Virtue: and therefore tho' he be not So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licitous about the Niceties or Punctilio's of Ceremony, yet ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:154250:44"/> this Law written in his Heart, all his Actions thence pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding must needs be Regular, Orderly, and Decent. There will hence be seen a Decorum in all his Conversation, that is not Superficial, but Essential; that is not Counterfeited, but Natural; that is not Transient, but Perma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent; as deriv'd from that Root which abides Ever, and <hi>fails not.</hi> There is an inexpressible Beauty in his Behaviour both to the Children of <hi>Men,</hi> and to the Children of <hi>God;</hi> that is insensi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly convey'd from the Supreme and Infinite Beauty. And this he calls the Reflexion of the Light of God's Countenance up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on his Soul.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian seeks not his Own.]</head>
                  <p>THere is nothing more con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tradicts the Beautiful Law
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:154250:45"/> of Order, than a narrow Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracted Spirit, which is Always <hi>Seeking its Own,</hi> and not that which is for the Good of the Whole. Wherefore a True <hi>Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ladelphian</hi> is the most Publick Spirited Person that can be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scrib'd. He seeks not his own Private Interest in the Publick: but tramples the former under his Feet, even with the utmost Disdain, so he may but promote the latter. And he doth not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly lay hold on every Opportuni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, that is presented to him, for the Exercise of this Publick, Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciful, and Beneficent Spirit: but even sedulously watches for, and catches after Opportunities, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Example of his Blessed MASTER, continually <hi>going a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hout doing Good.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <pb n="63" facs="tcp:154250:45"/>
                  <head>[A Philadelphian is not easily Provoked]</head>
                  <p>IT is not otherwise to be Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected but that a Person of a Publick Spirit, whose Study it is to do Good to Others, and to Advance the Honour and Interest of his Great and Glorious MA<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>STER, will meet with many Affronts, Misrepresentations, and Provocations from the Unthink<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing or Ungrateful Part of Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kind. But a True <hi>Philadelphian</hi> will not be hereat in the least Provok'd or Irritated. He lives above the Censure of the World, as being the Spectacle of God and of all his Holy Angels, and of all the Great and Good Men, now <hi>made perfect,</hi> who have e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver liv'd upon the Face of the Earth, and been the Benefactors of Human Kind. Wherefore looking stedfastly upon such as
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:154250:46"/> these, he matters not either the <hi>good or bad Report</hi> of the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent Age; but is Resolv'd to break through All, that he may be Serviceable to it, and to Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sterity. He will not be provok'd to lay down a Good and Noble Design, whatever Clamours may be raised against him: and will hazard both his Reputation and Fortune a Thousand Times over in this Life, rather then not to Do what he knows to be for the Honour of his GOD, and the Benefit of his Neighbour; and more specially if for that of a Kingdom. In short, he is so great a Master of himself, by the Grace and Spirit of Christ, that should all Mankind set themselves a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst him, they could not be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to cast him even into one Paroxysm.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <pb n="65" facs="tcp:154250:46"/>
                  <head>[Philadelphian thinketh no Evil.]</head>
                  <p>CAndour is the most Peculiar <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Characteri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stick: by which He is distin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guish'd, Visibly and Eminently, from all the Parties, Sects, and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ternal Denominations of Religion whatever. He is ever willing to take things in the Best Sense: and when two Opposite Constructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons may be put upon the same Matter, he constantly remembers the Council of that Good Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tur'd Philosopher, who charg'd his Pupil never to take up a Ves<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sel by the Left Handle, when he could hold it by the Right. So the True <hi>Philadelphian</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sidering how All Things have Two Handles, and how the ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry same Person is made both an Heroe and a Monster, according as the Painter is pleas'd to draw
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:154250:47"/> him; will suspend his Assent, till he can be Fully Ascertain'd, and will incline still to the more Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vourable Part. For</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian Rejoyceth not in Iniquity]</head>
                  <p>HE sets not up for a <hi>Critick</hi> upon the Failures of O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers: nor would Establish to himself the Reputation of a <hi>Wit</hi> upon the Weaknesses or Mistakes of Any. It is the Common Vice of the World to take a Pleasure in discoursing of the Folly or Knavery of others, (without which Topicks perhaps Nine Parts in Ten of Ordinary Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>versation would be Nothing:) And to Censure these is taken up as the most Easie Method to be thought a Man of Sense, or a Man of Probity. But the true <hi>Philadelphian</hi> Genius is quite o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwise: it minds not the im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pertinent
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:154250:47"/> or insignificant Buzzings of a Fly, or the ridiculous Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stures of a Monkey: it finds no delight in calling over the Poli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tical Fetches of a Cunning Fox, the Hypocrisie and Treachery of a Crocodile, or the Rapaci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Unmercifulness of a Wolf; nor is diverted in raking into Dung and Ordure. The <hi>Philadel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phian</hi> Spirit is far too Noble for any such Employment as this: and therefore, living above the Genius of this World, converses much with the Blessed Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of the Superiour Worlds; who <hi>think no Evil</hi> of one ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther; neither <hi>rejoyce in Iniquity,</hi> or the Failings of any of their Fellow Creatures; but <hi>rejoyce in the Truth,</hi> and in the Conformity of Things Below with Things Above, or with the Heavenly Patterns. By whom being In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>structed</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <pb n="68" facs="tcp:154250:48"/>
                  <head>[A Philadelphian rejoyceth in the Truth]</head>
                  <p>CAlumny is the very Nature of the Devil himself, who ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver rejoyces more than when he finds matter for his Accusations. And its Opposite Virtue is a Ray from the Divine Nature commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nicated to Blessed Angels, and Blessed Souls. Hereby the true <hi>Philadelphian</hi> is made most like to the Deity, which is <hi>Truth,</hi> and thence never <hi>rejoyces,</hi> but <hi>in the Truth,</hi> or in the Reflexion of his own immaculate Light. Wherefore the <hi>Philadelphian</hi> R<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyces not Alone, but <hi>with</hi> the Best Company: with the Holy Majesty of God, with the whole Court of Heaven, with all Good Men on Earth, and more par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticularly with Injur'd and Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pressed Innocence, that comes to be Vindicated by the <hi>Truth.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <pb n="69" facs="tcp:154250:48"/>
                  <head>[A Philadelphian concealeth all things.]</head>
                  <p>AS his great Care is to do no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing against Truth, so since the World is very little a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to Bear it, he is forc'd to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joy it by himself, together with this Secret Blessed Society, rather than to prostitute it to such as would trample it under their Feet. Wherefore a true <hi>Phila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delphian</hi> will <hi>bear,</hi> and <hi>keep all things</hi> in his <hi>Heart,</hi> that are not to be Communicated to Any but to the <hi>Wise;</hi> according to the most express Command and Caution of Christ himself, and his own Practice, with that of his Holy <hi>Mother</hi> and <hi>Apostles,</hi> and indeed of all the <hi>Prophets, Wisemen,</hi> and <hi>Scribes</hi> of the Kingdom in all Ages. This Gift of Taciturnity, and Holy Si<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence is most absolutely Requisite
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:154250:49"/> for him, as he stands ingag'd in Great Undertakings for the Glo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of God. For if the Secrets of Princes ought to be Sacred, then much more, thinks the True <hi>Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ladelphian,</hi> ought the Secrets of HIM <hi>By whom Princes Reign.</hi> And yet even his<note n="*" place="margin">
                        <hi>Psalm</hi> xxv. 14.</note>
                     <hi>Secrets are with them that fear Him.</hi> However this Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>citurnity or Reservedness, must not hinder but that he be Bold as a Lyon, to Declare and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mulgate all that he is Comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded by his Supreme LORD: and thus to <hi>bear up,</hi> and <hi>support</hi> as it were, under HIM, the Pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars of His Government. For</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian Believeth all Things.]</head>
                  <p>ON the Part of GOD he Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieves that He is Faithful and True to perform All his Promises even to the Minutest Title of 'em:
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:154250:49"/> and that he is no less ready Now to Assist them that <hi>Truly Believe</hi> in Him, than he was to Assist all the Antient Worthies, and Great Heroes: who are left as a<note place="margin">
                        <hi>Heb.</hi> xii. 1.</note>
                     <hi>Cloud of Witnesses,</hi> for us to follow their Steps. And on the Part of <hi>Man</hi> a True <hi>Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ladelphian</hi> will also <hi>believe all things,</hi> that upon any Probable Motives of Credibility can be produced either for Vindication, or Alleviation.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian Hopeth all Things.]</head>
                  <p>ON the Part of GOD he Hopes both for an <hi>Ordinary,</hi> and <hi>Extraordinary</hi> Appearance of His Majesty. The Ground of this Hope is upon a <hi>Rock:</hi> and nothing is too Great for it too reach after, in Advancing His Glory. And on the Part of <hi>Man,</hi> there where the <hi>Noto<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>iety</hi> of E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vil
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:154250:50"/> is too Plain, for him to <hi>Believe</hi> Good, yet he Despairs not, but hopes that even the most Diabolical Sinner may at length Repent, and become a very Great and Glorious <hi>Saint; Loving much, because much is Forgiven.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian Endureth all Things]</head>
                  <p>THis Heroical <hi>Faith</hi> and <hi>Hope</hi> makes the true <hi>Philadelphian</hi> to <hi>Endure</hi> and Suffer <hi>all things</hi> in his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sters Cause, and for His Sake. For al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways expecting Him to <hi>come quickly,</hi> he will never flinch Back, but will <hi>keep the Word of his Patience,</hi> &amp; will remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber to hold <hi>that fast which</hi> he hath, <hi>that no Man take</hi> his <hi>Crown.</hi> Wherefore</p>
               </div>
               <div type="characteristic">
                  <head>[A Philadelphian never faileth.]</head>
                  <p>BUT when all other Names of Distinction shall fail, and be burnt up, this shall Abide. The <hi>Name</hi> of a PHILADELPHIAN <hi>shall en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dure for ever: it shall be continued as long as the Sun: and all Nations shall call him the Bles<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed of the</hi> LORD.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="conclusion">
                  <p>These were the <hi>Marks</hi> that were given to a certain Traveller toward the Heavenly City of PHILADELPHIA, by a strong Angel that de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scended thence, who having taken out his Heart, left as it were a <hi>Flaming Coal</hi> in the Room thereof; which <hi>Burns</hi> incessantly with most Vehement Desires, for the Good of All his Brethren, that is, of All Mankind.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:50"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:51"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:154250:51"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>